<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tutorial on john-shiver</title>
    <link>http://www.johnshiver.org/tags/tutorial/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tutorial on john-shiver</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.johnshiver.org/tags/tutorial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing Merge Sort in Python</title>
      <link>http://www.johnshiver.org/posts/merge-sort/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.johnshiver.org/posts/merge-sort/</guid>
      <description>Imagine having a phone book without the last names sorted alphabetically. Or a dictionary with words unorganized. Ever tried to find a web page on the internet without the help of a search engine to rank results by relevance?
All of these tools derive their usefulness primarily from presenting information that has been sorted. Sorting algorithms are one of the key areas of research within computer science. After all, data is mostly useless without some sort of structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing a Singly Linked List in Python</title>
      <link>http://www.johnshiver.org/posts/singly-linked-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.johnshiver.org/posts/singly-linked-list/</guid>
      <description>A lot of self-taught programmers don’t realize the importance of these concepts until they already have an interview lined up, and by then it’s already too late! I was fortunate enough to attend the Code Fellows Python Development Accelerator, where a section of the curriculum was dedicated to basic data structures and algorithms. But eight whirlwind weeks were not enough to solidify these concepts, so I thought it’d be beneficial, both for my own edification and for other budding Pythonistas, to write a series on basic data structures, starting with the linked list.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>